# MALCOLM FRANKLIN

#### Denver, CO

Phone: 360-525-7403 | Email: Malcolm.Franklin.M@gmail.com |

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{LinkedIn: } \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/mmalcolmm/} & | \textbf{Portfolio: } \underline{https://MalcolmFranklin.onrender.com} \\ \textbf{SUMMARY} \\ \end{tabular}$ 

Full-stack web developer with a background in dispatching. Trained at University of Denver coding boot camp and earned a certificate in full-stack web development. Innovative problem-solver passionate about developing apps; focused on mobile-first design and development. Strengths in creativity, teamwork, and building projects from ideation to execution.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### **Front-end Development:**

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript (and frameworks like React.js)
- Bootstrap and Bulma
- Responsive Design principles

## **Back-end Development:**

- Node.js/Express.js
- postgresSQL, SQL

#### **PROJECTS**

# Dark Whispers | <a href="https://github.com/sentorus67/DarkWhispers">https://github.com/sentorus67/DarkWhispers</a> | Link to Deployed Project <a href="https://darkwhispers.onrender.com/">https://darkwhispers.onrender.com/</a>

Dark Whispers is an interactive text-based adventure game designed to provide users with a captivating and immersive experience. The project is built using modern web development technologies and follows the Model-View-Controller (MVC) architectural pattern to ensure a clear separation of concerns and maintainability.

- My core responsibilities were handling user authentication, creating and seeding the database and creating the server.
- The website uses Bulma for styling, JWT token for security and authentication, berypt to hash passwords and Handlebars.js for the template engine.

Animals and Fables | https://github.com/sentorus67/AnimalsandFables |

## https://sentorus67.github.io/AnimalsandFables/

- Project uses two APIs to generate a random animal and stories about or relating to the animal then renders them to the page.
- My core responsibilities were styling with a mobile-first approach and assisting with JavaScript functions, Using Bulma, jQuery, API-Ninjas/animals and Gutendex.

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Dispatcher 2022 - current

#### Federal Protective Service, Denver, CO

Monitor alarms and dispatch officers to government buildings. Effectively work with a team, relying heavily on verbal and written communication to get responders to a scene efficiently.

#### **Operations Manager 2021-2022**

# G2 Secure Staff, Denver, CO

Worked with United to handle all of their fueling, wheelchair assistance and aircraft cleaning. Managed a team of approximately 100 employees and worked to ensure there were no delays on outbound flights.

#### **Dispatcher 2018-2021**

#### Icom Dispatch, Oak Harbor, WA

Dispatched for law, fire and EMS, taking emergency and non-emergency calls. Working in a very team-based setting we relied on our partners having room awareness and making notifications to responders without being asked.

#### Store Manager 2015-2018

#### T-mobile, Oak Harbor WA

Managed a team of 5-8 employees, overseeing the daily operations of the retail store, ensuring exceptional customer service and achieving sales targets. Trained new hires on company policies, products, and sales techniques, while also providing ongoing coaching and development opportunities for existing team members.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Program Certificate:** University of Denver – In-progress with an anticipated graduation date of August 13<sup>th</sup>, 2024. A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining skills in Full-stack web development.